aclj.org 2002-06-02

# Privacy Statement

| 

**  
Privacy Statement**

By accessing or using the ACLJ Web Site, you agree to the terms of the ACLJ Web Site Online Privacy Policy, as outlined below. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not access or use this site. The ACLJ Web Site reserves the right to change the Online Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion. Your use of this site will be subject to the most current version of the Online Privacy Policy at the time of such use.

**Collection of Personal Information**  
When you engage in certain activities on this site, such as ordering information, signing petitions, making donations, sending emails or requests to the ACLJ, downloading forms, or requesting newsletter or email subscriptions etc., the ACLJ Web Site may ask you to provide certain information about yourself by filling out and submitting an online form. It is completely optional for you to engage in these activities. If you elect to engage in these activities, however, the ACLJ Web Site may ask that you provide us personal information, such as your first and last name, mailing address (including zip code), E-mail address, employer, job title and department, telephone and facsimile numbers, and other personal identifying information.   If you do not provide the requested data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity.

**How Your Personal Information is Used**  
The ACLJ Web Site collects your information in order to record and support your participation in the activities you select. For example, if you participate in petition drives, emails to Ask Jay a question, or request assistance from the ACLJ, your information is used to contact you and send appropriate materials.

**Use of Personal Information**  
The ACLJ Web Site recognizes and appreciates the importance of responsible use of information collected on this site. For this reason, the ACLJ reserves the option of contacting you at least one time about important issues in which the ACLJ is involved. At that time, and with each subsequent email, the ACLJ will provide you with the opportunity to "opt out" using our automated system. If you choose this option, you will receive no further email from the ACLJ.   
On occasion, the ACLJ Web Site may selectively provide certain information to other companies or organizations that have products or services that we think may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive email regarding third party products or services, please "opt out" by sending an email with you name, address + zip and phone number to [acljmail@exis.net](mailto:acljmail@exis.net) or you may write or send a postcard to: 

ACLJ -"Third Party Opt Out"   
P.O.Box 64429  
Virginia Beach, VA 23467

Please include your full name, address, zip and phone number when corresponding with us. 

**  
Protection of Your Personal Information**  
The personal information that you provide in connection with making a donation to the ACLJ using the ACLJ Web Site, classifies your data as Donor Registration Information. Donor Registration Information is protected in several ways. First, it resides on a secure server that only selected ACLJ Web Site personnel and its authorized users have access to via password. Second, the ACLJ Web Site encrypts your personal information and thereby prevents unauthorized parties from viewing it. Personal information that you provide when registering for a petition, or corresponding with the ACLJ, for example, also resides on a secure server and is only accessible via password, however it is not encrypted. 

****

**Use of Cookies**  
The ACLJ Web Site currently uses cookies to reduce loading time.    ****

**Updating Your Personal Information**  
You have the right to access and correct your personal information at any time. With respect to Donor or Registration Information, this may be accomplished by contacting us using our [Email Messaging Center](https://www.donation-net.net/email/e_trans.cfm?dn=1008).      

You may also access and correct your personal information and privacy preferences by writing or calling ACLJ Web Site at:

**The ACLJ Web Site**  
P.O.Box 64429  
Virginia Beach, VA 23467  
(757) 226-2489  
(757) 226-2836 (fax)

**Privacy Related Complaints**  
If you believe that the ACLJ Web Site has not complied with this Online Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information, you may write the ACLJ Web Site Privacy Officer at the address indicated above. 

In your letter, please describe in as much detail as possible the ways in which you believe that the ACLJ has not complied with the Official Web Site Online Privacy Policy. We will investigate your complaint promptly.

Please note that if you provide ACLJ Web Site with inconsistent privacy preferences (for example, by indicating on one occasion that third parties may contact you with marketing offers and indicating on another occasion that they may not), ACLJ Web Site cannot guarantee that your most recent privacy preference will be honored.

Also, please note that ACLJ Web Site is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of non-ACLJ Web sites to which we may link.
